Guide to the BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 1)
BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 1)
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 1)
1942- 1981
6178/001
United States Department of Labor; Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS)
22 linear ft.
Records (documents), collective labor agreements.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
22 cubic feet
The US Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) was established in 1884 to collect information about employment and labor in the United States. As mandated by the 1947 Taft-Hartley Act, the BLS was formally tasked with responsibility for soliciting, collecting, and analyzing collective bargaining agreements (CBAs) from public and private establishments, and making the agreements publicly available. In the early 1980s, this was function was limited to union contracts made with employers of 1000 or more employees.
In 2002, the National Archives and Records Administration authorized the BLS to donate inactive, non-confidential agreements which were 5 years or more past their expiration date to the Kheel Center where they would be preserved and made available to the public. The Office of Labor-Management Services took over responsibility for collecting and analyzing CBAs in 2011, and continues this donor relationship with the Kheel Center.
The US Department of Labor Historical Collective Bargaining Agreements Collection, 6178, is made up of 21 series of expired public- and private-sector collective bargaining agreements dating from 1887 to 2003 and totals 685 linear feet plus 10 CDs of digitized documents and 320 reels of microfilm. In addition to the CBAs, a small volume of related documents such as union constitutions, pension and health plans submitted to the BLS, are also available.
Selected collective bargaining agreements from this collection were digitized with generous funding from the National Historic Publications and Records Commission (NHPRC), and the National Science Foundation (NSF). Because documents other than collective bargaining agreements were also collected and preserved here by the US Department of Labor, a folder containing material that has been digitized, may also contain material which has not been digitized such as constitutions, bylaws, working rules, life insurance plans, or other organizational documents. For access to non-digitized material, contact Kheel Center staff.
United States. Department of Labor -- Archives.; United States. Bureau of Labor Statistics -- Archives.; Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America -- Archives; Upholsterers' International Union of North America-- Archives; International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite, and Paper Mill Workers. Local 150--Archives; United Steelworkers of America -- Archives; Textile Workers Union of America-- Archives; Oil, Chemical, and Atomic Workers International Union -- Archives; International Union of United Rubber, Cork, Linoleum, and Plastic Workers of America-- Archives; United Shoe Workers of America. Joint Council 13 -- Archives; International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America-- Archives; International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers -- Archives; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers-- Archives; International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers -- Archives; United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America--Archives; Communications Workers of America--Archives; International Brotherhood of Teamsters-- Archives; Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union--Archives; Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America-- Archives; Hotel & Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union-- Archives; Insurance Workers International Union -- Archives; Building Service Employees' International Union--Archives; International Association of Cleaning and Dye House Workers-- Archives; Screen Directors International Guild --Archives; American Federation of Musicians -- Archives; Hygrade Food Products Corporation -- Archives; California Sportswear and Dress Association -- Archives; Uniroyal, inc. -- Archives; International Harvester Company -- Archives; Western Union Telegraph Company-- Archives; Montgomery Ward -- Archives; Great Atlantic & Pacific Tea Company-- Archives
Pharmacists -- Labor unions --United States; Butchers -- Labor unions --United States; Collective labor agreements -- Uphostry trade -- United States; Collective labor agreements -- Paper industry -- United States; Rubber industry workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Electricians --Labor unions-- United States; Carpenters -- Labor unions -- United States; Retail trade -- Employees--Labor unions -- United States; Collective labor agreements - United States.
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Collections: 6178/002: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 2) 6178/003: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 3) 6178/004: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 4) 6178/006: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 6) 6178/007: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 7) 6178/008: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 8) 6178/009: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 9) 6178/010: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 10) 6178/011: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 11) 6178/012: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 12) 6178/013: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 13) 6178/014: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 14) 6178/015: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 15) 6178/016: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 16) 6178/017: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 17) 6178/018: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 18) 6178/019: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 19) 6178/020: OLMS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 20) 6178/021(d): BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 21) Digital 6178/022 mf: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 22) on Microfilm 6178/023: OLMS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 23) 6178: BLS/OLMS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements
Series I: Industry Code #11, Agriculture, Forestry, Fishing and Hunting
Series II: Industry Code #21, Mining, Quarrying, and Oil and Gas Extraction
Series III: Industry Code #22, Utilities
Series IV: Industry Code #23, Construction
Series V: Industry Code #31, Manufacturing
Series VI: Industry Code #32, Manufacturing
Series VII: Industry Code #33, Manufacturing
Series VIII: Industry Code #42, Wholesale Trade
Series IX: Industry Code #44, Retail Trade
Series X: Industry Code #45, Retail Trade
Series XI: Industry Code #48, Transportation and Warehousing
Series XII: Industry Code #49, Transportation and Warehousing
Series XIII: Industry Code #51, Information
Series XIV: Industry Code #52, Finance and Insurance
Series XV: Industry Code #54, Professional, Scientific, and Technical Services
Series XVI: Industry Code #55, Management of Companies and Enterprises
Series XVII: Industry Code #56, Administrative and Support and Waste Management and Remediation Services
Series XVIII: Code #62, Health Care and Social Assistance
Series XIX: Code #71, Arts, Entertainment, and Recreation
Series XX: Code #72, Accommodation and Food Services
Series XXI: Code #81, Other Services (except Public Administration)
- Series I: Industry Code #11, Agriculture, Forestry, Fishing and Hunting
  - Code no.8200: Tree Fruits Labor Relations Committee, Inc. and Fruit and Vegetable Packers and Warehousemen's Union, Local 760, 1957- 1960 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Code no.8203: Purse Seine Vessel Owners Marketing Association and International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, Local 3, 1961-1965 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Code no.6322 / 591364: Grower-Shipper Vegetable Association of Central California and United Packinghouse Food and Allied Workers of America, Local 78A, 1965-1971 (Box 20, Folder 18)
- Series II: Industry Code #21, Mining, Quarrying, and Oil and Gas Extraction
  - Code no.8300: Iron and Mining Companies: Cleveland-Cliffs, Negaunee, Humboldt, Marquette, Empire and United Steelworkers of America, AFL-CIO, 1960-1971 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Code no.8311: Climax Molybdenum Co. and Oil, Chemical and Atomic Workers International Union, AFL, CIO, Local 2-24410, 1959- 1971 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Code no.8312: Award of the Antrhacite Coal Strike Commission. Anthracite Operators and the International Union United Mine Workers of American, Districts 1, 7, 9, 1964-1975 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Code no.8313: Award of the Antrhacite Coal Strike Commission. Anthracite Operators and the International Union United Mine Workers of American, Districts 1, 7, 9, 1968-1977 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Code no.8321: Mining Companies, Lake Superior Region and United Steelworkers of America, 1962-1965 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Code no.8324-1: Reserve Mining Company and United Steelworkers of America, 1962-1965 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Code no.8324-2: Reserve Mining Company and United Steelworkers of America, 1968-1971 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Code no.8328: Homestake Mining Company and United Steelworkers of America, 1966-1972 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Code no.8333: Tennessee Copper Company and International Chemical Workers Union, Local 401, 1961-1969 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Code no.8334: Limpus Quarries, Inc. and International Union of Operating Engineers, Local 101; Heavy Construction Laborers' Local 663; Teamsters Local 541, 1974-1977 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Code no.8773: American Dredging Company; Dredge Owners Protective Association and International Union of Operating Engineers, Local 25, Marine Division, AFL-CIO, 1968-1971 (Box 19, Folder 16)
- Series III: Industry Code #22, Utilities
  - Code no.6031: Tennessee Valley Authority and Salary Policy Employee Panel, 1950-1976 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Code no.6032-2: Tennessee Valley Authority and Tennessee Valley Trades and Labor Council, 1971-1977 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Code no.6033: Tennessee Valley Authority and Tennessee Valley Trades and Labor Council, 1969-1977 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Code no.6068-2: Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, AFL-CIO, Locals 1339, 1352, 79, 478, 554, 836, 1484, 137, 1369, 1371, 1385, 1966-1973 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Code no.6071: Pacific Gas and Electric Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 1245, 1960-1970 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Code no.6081-1: Wisconsin Public Service Corporation and International Union of Operating Engineers, Local 310, 1961-1973 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Code no.6085-1: Columbus and Southern Ohio Electric Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 1466, 1962- 1971 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Code no.6090-1: Central Maine Power Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 839, 1966-1970 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Code no.1675 / 591073: Union Carbide Nuclear Company, Division of Union Carbide Corporation, Oak Ridge National Laboratory and Atomic Trades and Labor Council, AFL-CIO, 1961-1968 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Code no.6052 / 591090: Atlantic Seaboard Corporation and Oil, Chemical, and Atomic Workers International U Union, Locals 3-372, 3-628, 1961-1975 (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Series IV: Industry Code #23, Construction
  - Code no.1809-1: Beaumont Refinery, Mobil Oil Corporation and Oil, Chemical, and Atomic Workers International Union, Local 4-243, 1972- 1979 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Code no.1812: Shell Oil Company and Oil, Chemical and Atomic Workers International Union, Local 4-367, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Code no.1818: Texaco, Inc., Port Arthur Plant and Terminal and Oil, Chemical and Atomic Workers International Union, Local 4-23, 1962- 1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Code no.8330: Connecticut Construction Industries Association and International Union of Operating Engineers, Local 47, AFL-CIO, 1972- 1974 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Code no.8400: Associated Building Contractors of Terre Haute, Indiana and International Hod Carriers, Building and Common Laborers Union, Local 57, 1959-1971 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Code no.8406: Associated General Contractors of America and Carpenters, Piledrivers, Millwrights of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, 1959-1961 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Code no.8407: Associated General Contractors of America and State Council of Carpenters, 1959-1962 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Code no.8408: Portland Chapter, Associated General Contractors of America and Oregon State District Council of Laborers, 1959- 1967 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Code no.8409: Associated General Contractors of America and Operating Engineers, Local 428, 1973-1976 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Code no.8411: Southern California General Contractors and Teamsters Joint Council No. 42, Teamsters Local Union No. 87, 1962- 1968 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Code no.8414: Oregon-Columbia Chapter, Associated General Contractors of America and International Union of Operating Engineers, Local 701, 1967-1976 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Code no.8415: Associated General Contractors of St. Louis and Eastern Missouri Laborers' District Council, AFL-CIO, Locals 42, 53, 110, 1960- 1963 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Code no.8416: Associated General Contractors of America, Detroit Chapter and International Hod Carriers' Building and Common Laborers' Union, AFL-CIO, Locals 334, 1076, 1191, 1960-1970 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Code no.8417: Associated General Contractors of America, San Diego Chapter and Building and Construction Trades Unions, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Local 36, 1960-1972 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Code no.8419: Associated General Contractors Employers Association of Omaha, Nebraska and International Hod Carriers, Building and Common Laborers' Union of America, Local 1140, 1962-1965 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Code no.8420: Associated General Contractors of America, Alabama Branch and Labor International Union of North America, Local 559, 1967- 1968 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Code no.8421: Carpenters' District Council of Miami, Florida and Vicinity and United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, AFL-CIO, 1969-1975 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Code no.8422: Minneapolis and St. Paul Builders Divisions and Building Trades Unions, Locals 1 and 2, 1960-1966 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Code no.8423: Associated General Contractors of Minnesota, Minneapolis and St. Paul Divisions and Twin City Carpenters District Council, 1963-1969 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Code no.8426: Associated General Contractors of Minnesota, Minneapolis and St. Paul Divisions and Construction and General Laborers Union, Local 563, AFL-CIO, 1966-1972 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Code no.8427: Nevada Chapter, Associated General Contractors of America and United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners, Local 1780, 1961-1968 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Code no.8428: Associated General Contractors of America, Mountain Pacific, Tacoma, and Seattle Northwest chapters and International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 1961-1971 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Code no.8431: Building Trades Employers Association of Westchester and Putnam Counties and International Union of Operating Engineers, Locals 137, 137A, 137B, 1961-1964 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Code no.8432: Builders' Association of Chicago and Construction and General Laborers' District Council of Chicago and Vicinity, 1947- 1972 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    1947-1950 1963-1972
  - Code no.8433: Builders Association of Chicago and United Order of American Bricklayers and Stone Masons' Union, Local 21, 1957- 1969 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Code no.8435: Builders Association of Kansas City, Missouri and Building Material, Excavating, Heavy Haulers, Drivers, Warehousemen and Helpers Local Union 541, 1960-1971 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Code no.8437: Building and Commercial Laborers' District Council and International Hod Carriers, Building and Common Laborers' Union, Local 74, 1961-1963 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Code no.8439: Construction Contractors Council and Carpenters' District Council of Washington D.C. and Vicinity, 1959-1976 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Code no.8446: Dayton Area Construction Industry Association and Miami Valley Carpenters' District Council, 1960-1966 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Code no.8447: Eastern New York Construction Employers and Albany, Schenectady, Troy, and Vicinity District Council of Carpenters, 1963- 1970 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Code no.8448: General Contractors Association and Building, Concrete, Excavating and Common Laborers Union, Local 31, 1960- 1966 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Code no.8449: General Contractors Association of Bridgeport, CT and Carpenters District Council of Bridgeport, CT, 1961-1969 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Code no.8451: Hartford General Contractors Association and United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 43, 1961- 1966 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Code no.8454: Middle Tennessee District Council of Carpenters and United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, 1958- 1975 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Code no.8457: Master Builders Association of Bergen County and Bergen County Conference, Locals 23, 25, 28, 32, 44, 1961-1974 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Code no.8458: Ohio Valley Builders Exchange, Inc. and United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Steel Valley District Council, 1959-1961 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Code no.8460: Southwestern Michigan Contractors Association and Southwestern Michigan Carpenters District Council of United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners, AFL-CIO, 1959-1973 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Code no.8463: Associated General Contractors of America, Intermountain Branch and Operating Engineers, Local 3 of the International Union of Operating Engineers, 1960-1966 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Code no.8464: Associated General Contractors of America, Intermountain Branch and Laborers District Council of the State of Utah, 1960- 1966 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Code no.8465: Spokane Chapter and Eastern Washington Builders, Associated General Contractors and Eastern Washington District Council of Laborers, Idaho District, 1959-1965 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Code no.8466: Associated General Contractors of New Jersey and International Hod Carriers, Building and Common Laborers' Union of America, Local 172, 1959-1962 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Code no.8467: Associated General Contractors of America, Central and Northern California chapters and International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 1957-1962 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Code no.8468: Associated General Contractors of America, Northern and Central California Chapter and Operating Engineers Local Union 3, 1962-1972 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Code no.8469: Associated General Contractors of America, Spokane and Eastern Washington Chapters and International Union of Operating Engineers, Local 370, 1960-1965 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Code no.8470: Labor Relations Division, Heavy and Highway Construction and Laborers International Union of North America, 1960- 1974 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Code no.8471: Associated General Contractors of America, Inc. Spokane Chapter and International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Locals 690, 551, 148, 556, 839, 1955-1958 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Code no.8472: Associated General Contractors of America, Utah Chapter and United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, 1972- 1976 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Code no.8473: Associated General Contractors of Minnesota and International Union of Operating Engineers, Local 49, 1960-1965 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Code no.8474: Portland Chapter, Associated General Contractors of America and Oregon State District Council of Laborers, 1961- 1967 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Code no.8476: Contractors Association of Westchester County and International Hod Carriers, Building and Common Laborers Local 60, 1958- 1970 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Code no.8479: Labor Relations Division of Michigan Road Builders Association and Michigan Conference of Teamsters Local Unions, 1959- 1967 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Code no.8480: Connecticut Labor Relations Division of the New England Road Builders' Association and Hoisting and Portable Engineers Local Union 478, International Union of Operating Engineers, 1961-1974 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Code no.8481: Connecticut Construction Industries Association and Connecticut State Council of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, 1973-1977 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Code no.8482: Massachusetts Labor Relations Division of New England Road Builders' Association and International Hod Carriers' Building and Common Laborers' Union of America, AFL-CIO, 1959-1962 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Code no.8483: Connecticut Labor Relations Division of the New England Road Builders' Association and Construction Division of the Joint Council 64, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 1960-1977 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Code no.8487: Northern and Central California Chapter, Associated General Contractors of America and United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, 1957-1969 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Code no.8490: Piledriving Contractors' Association, Northern and Central California Chapters of the Associated General Contractors of America and Piledrivers, Bridge, Wharf and Dockbuilders, Local 34, 1960-1971 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Code no.8495: Heavy Constructors Association of Greater Kansas City and Laborers' District Council of Greater Kansas Cities, 1960- 1974 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Code no.8496: Heavy Constructors Association of Greater Kansas City and International Union of Operating Engineers, Hoisting and Portable Local Union 101, AFL-CIO, 1960-1974 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Code no.8497: Missouri River Basin Firms and International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Ship Builders, Blacksmiths, Forgers and Helpers, 1960-1967 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Code no.8499: South Central Employers and International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Ship Builders, Blacksmiths, Forgers and Helpers, 1962-1973 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Code no.8501: Underground Contractors Association and Sewer and Tunnel Miners Union, Local 2, 1961-1966 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Code no.8504: Associated General Contractors of America, Southern California and San Diego Chapters and Local Unions 114, 202, 230, 250, 364, 398, 403, 484, 1957-1972 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Code no.8505: Greater Bay Area Association of Plumbing, Piping and Air Conditioning Contractors and United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry of the United States and Canada, Local 393, 1961-1969 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Code no.8507: Detroit Association of Plumbing Contractors; Mechanical Contractors' Association and Journeymen Plumbers, Local 98 of Detroit, 1958-1970 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Code no.8509: United Association of Plumbing and Pipefitting Industry and Employees of the Plumbing and Pipefitting Industry, State of Washington, 1959-1967 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Code no.8510: National Automatic Sprinkler and Fire Control Association and United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry of the United States and Canada, Local 393, 1960-1964 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Code no.8532: National Electrical Contractors Association and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 11, 1961-1969 (Box 17, Folder 1)